export default {
  id: 'mid_1_1a',
  name: '상용한자(중학1/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '介', answer: ['끼일 개', '끼일', 'かい'] },
    { question: '傘', answer: ['우산 산', 'かさ', 'さん'] },
    { question: '脊', answer: ['척추 척', '척추', 'せき'] },
    { question: '込', answer: ['담을 입', 'こ(む)、こ(める)', ''] },
    { question: '汰', answer: ['일 태', '일', 'た'] },
    { question: '駄', answer: ['실을 태, 실을 타', '실을', 'だ'] },
    { question: '咲', answer: ['웃음 소', 'さく', ''] },
    { question: '朕', answer: ['나 짐', '나', 'ちん'] },
    { question: '扶', answer: ['도울 부', '도울', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '替', answer: ['바꿀 체', 'か(える)、か(わる)', 'たい'] },
    { question: '潜', answer: ['잠길 잠', 'ひそ(む)、もぐ(る)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '抜', answer: ['뽑을 발', 'ぬ(く)、ぬ(ける)、ぬ(かす)、ぬ(かる)', 'ばつ'] },
    { question: '髪', answer: ['머리털 발', 'かみ', 'はつ'] },
    { question: '伏', answer: ['엎드릴 복', 'ふ(せる)、ふ(す)', 'ふく'] },
    { question: '突', answer: ['갑자기 돌', 'つ(く)', 'とつ'] },
    { question: '獄', answer: ['감옥 옥', '감옥', 'ごく'] },
    { question: '獣', answer: ['짐승 수', 'けもの', 'じゅう'] },
    { question: '玩', answer: ['희롱할 완', '희롱할', 'がん'] },
    { question: '匹', answer: ['짝 필', 'ひき', 'ひつ'] },
    { question: '克', answer: ['이길 극', '이길', 'こく'] },
    { question: '枕', answer: ['베개 침', 'まくら', ''] },
    { question: '沈', answer: ['잠길 침', 'しず(む)、しず(める)', 'ちん'] },
    { question: '況', answer: ['상황 황', '상황', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '呪', answer: ['빌 주', 'のろ(う)', 'じゅ'] },
    { question: '閲', answer: ['검열할 열', '검열할', 'えつ'] },
    { question: '悦', answer: ['기쁠 열', '기쁠', 'えつ'] },
    { question: '鋭', answer: ['날카로울 예', 'するど(い)', 'えい'] },
    { question: '脱', answer: ['벗을 탈', 'ぬ(ぐ)、ぬ(げる)', 'だつ'] },
    { question: '粒', answer: ['낟알 립', 'つぶ', 'りゅう'] },
    { question: '拉', answer: ['끌고갈 랍', '끌고갈', 'ら'] },
    { question: '普', answer: ['보통 보', '보통', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '譜', answer: ['족보 보', '족보', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '培', answer: ['북돋울 배', 'つちか(う)', 'ばい'] },
    { question: '陪', answer: ['모실 배', '모실', 'ばい'] },
    { question: '賠', answer: ['배상할 배', '배상할', 'ばい'] },
    { question: '剖', answer: ['쪼갤 부', '쪼갤', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '憶', answer: ['기억할 억', '기억할', 'おく'] },
    { question: '臆', answer: ['가슴 억', '가슴', 'おく'] },
    { question: '彰', answer: ['드러날 창', '드러날', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '潤', answer: ['불을 윤', 'うるお(う)、うるお(す)、うる(む)', 'じゅん'] },
    { question: '闇', answer: ['어두울 암', 'やみ', ''] },
    { question: '閑', answer: ['한가할 한', '한가할', 'かん'] },
    { question: '竜', answer: ['용 룡', 'たつ', 'りゅう'] },
    { question: '滝', answer: ['비올 롱', 'たき', ''] },
    { question: '籠', answer: ['대바구니 롱', 'かご、こも(る)', 'ろう'] },
    { question: '襲', answer: ['엄습할 습', 'おそ(う)', 'しゅう'] },
    { question: '嫡', answer: ['정실 적', '정실', 'ちゃく'] },
    { question: '摘', answer: ['딸 적', 'つ(む)', 'てき'] },
    { question: '滴', answer: ['물방울 적', 'しずく、したた(る)', 'てき'] },
    { question: '帝', answer: ['임금 제', '임금', 'てい'] },
    { question: '締', answer: ['맺을 체', 'し(まる)、し(める)', 'てい'] },
    { question: '諦', answer: ['살필 체', 'あきら(める)', 'てい'] },
    { question: '傍', answer: ['곁 방', 'かたわ(ら)', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '辛', answer: ['매울 신', 'から(い)', 'しん'] },
    { question: '宰', answer: ['재상 재', '재상', 'さい'] },
    { question: '執', answer: ['잡을 집', 'と(る)', 'しつ、しゅう'] },
    { question: '摯', answer: ['잡을 지', '잡을', 'し'] },
    { question: '僕', answer: ['종 복', '종', 'ぼく'] },
    { question: '撲', answer: ['칠 박', '칠', 'ぼく'] },
    { question: '旬', answer: ['열흘 순', '열흘', 'じゅん、(しゅん)'] },
    { question: '殉', answer: ['따라죽을 순', '따라죽을', 'じゅん'] },
    { question: '拘', answer: ['잡을 구', '잡을', 'こう'] },
    { question: '駒', answer: ['망아지 구', 'こま', ''] },
    { question: '抱', answer: ['안을 포', 'だ(く)、いだ(く)、かか(える)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '泡', answer: ['거품 포', 'あわ', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '砲', answer: ['대포 포', '대포', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '胞', answer: ['세포 포', '세포', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '飽', answer: ['배부를 포', 'あ(きる)、あ(かす)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '勾', answer: ['굽을 구', '굽을', 'こう'] },
    { question: '匂', answer: ['향내 내', 'にお(う)', ''] },
    { question: '酌', answer: ['술따를 작', 'く(む)', 'しゃく'] },
    { question: '釣', answer: ['낚을 조', 'つ(る)', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '喝', answer: ['꾸짖을 갈', '꾸짖을', 'かつ'] },
    { question: '渇', answer: ['목마를 갈', 'かわく', 'かつ'] },
    { question: '褐', answer: ['갈색 갈', '갈색', 'かつ'] },
    { question: '葛', answer: ['칡 갈', 'くず', 'かつ'] },
    { question: '掲', answer: ['걸 게, 높이들 게', 'かか(げる)', 'けい'] },
    { question: '謁', answer: ['뵐 알, 아뢸 알', '뵐, 아뢸', 'えつ'] },
    { question: '吹', answer: ['불 취', 'ふ(く)', 'すい'] },
    { question: '炊', answer: ['불땔 취', 'た(く)', 'すい'] },
    { question: '恣', answer: ['마음대로 자', '마음대로', 'し'] },
    { question: '茨', answer: ['가시나무 자', '[いばら]', ''] },
    { question: '諮', answer: ['물을 자', 'はか(る)', 'し'] },
    { question: '盗', answer: ['훔칠 도', 'ぬす(む)', 'とう'] },
    { question: '羨', answer: ['부러워할 선', 'うらや(む)、うらや(ましい)', 'せん'] },
    { question: '刃', answer: ['칼날 인', 'は', 'じん'] },
    { question: '忍', answer: ['참을 인', 'しの(ぶ)、しの(ばせる)', 'にん'] },
    { question: '那', answer: ['어찌 나', '어찌', 'な'] },
    { question: '召', answer: ['부를 소', 'め(す)', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '沼', answer: ['못 소', 'ぬま', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '紹', answer: ['이을 소', '이을', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '詔', answer: ['알릴 조', 'みことのり', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '窃', answer: ['훔칠 절', '훔칠', 'せつ'] },
    { question: '脅', answer: ['위협할 협', 'おびや(かす)、おど(す)、おど(かす)', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '脇', answer: ['겨드랑이 협', 'わき', ''] },
    { question: '架', answer: ['꾸밀 가, 시렁 가', 'か(ける)、か(かる)', 'か'] },
    { question: '拐', answer: ['후릴 괴, 유괴할 괴', '후릴, 유괴할', 'かい'] },
    { question: '劣', answer: ['못날 렬', 'おと(る)', 'れつ'] },
    { question: '施', answer: ['베풀 시', 'ほどこ(す)', 'し、せ'] }
  ]
}
